ecolint.ch 2019-05-08

# Privacy Policy | Ecolint | International School of Geneva

## Use of Personal Data

We collect and process personal data which you voluntarily provide by sending us an email, applying for a job, accepting an offer of employment, participating in a survey, completing an online form, or enrolling yourself or your children in our school or one of our related services such as holiday camps, our Centre des arts, our alumni membership platform or a further education training course.

We create and process personal data files about our current and future students, clients and alumni in order to evaluate and deal with their registration and admission as well as to manage any subsequent contractual relationship with the concerned data subject or their legal representative(s).

We do the same regarding job applicants and our current employees for the purposes of the recruiting process and if applicable the management of the subsequent employment relationship.

We also collect personal data which are freely accessible in the public domain about potential fundraising prospects or donors in order to secure the legitimate interests of financial support for the Foundation.

Personal data relating to tuition fee payments or fundraising activities is exclusively used for internal, statistical or fundraising purposes.

All personal data collection and analysis is done in compliance with both the applicable Swiss and European data protection laws and the corresponding data are treated confidentially.

We will only share personal data with affiliates for the purposes of conducting the activities and business of the school and provision of related services. The personal data collected will not be disclosed to third parties without the prior consent of the data subject or their legal representative(s).

## Consent to Personal Data Processing

By providing data to the International School of Geneva (hereinafter “Ecolint”), you confirm that pursuant to the provision of Article 4 (11) of the GDPR (General Data Protection Regulation UE 2016/679) in force as of May 25, 2018, Ecolint, with its registered seat at 62 Route de Chêne, 1208, Geneva, Switzerland, as a data controller, may process and subsequently use or further communicate your personal data for the purposes of conducting its educational business and activities and for sending communications related to the school and its associated services. This consent is also considered as the consent to send electronic mail messages and SMS messages under the GDPR provisions. At the same time you agree that the controller may also process your personal data through a data processor under the terms and conditions set out by the GDPR. We have contracts in place with our data processors. This means that they cannot do anything with your personal data unless we have instructed them to do it. They will not share your personal data with any organization apart from us. They will hold it securely and retain it for the period we instruct.

The consent is provided for an unlimited period until it is revoked.

In some circumstances we are legally obliged to share information. For example under a court order or where we cooperate with other European or Swiss supervisory authorities in handling complaints or investigations. We might also share information with other regulatory bodies in order to comply with their, or our, objectives. In any scenario, we will satisfy ourselves that we have a lawful basis on which to share the information and document our decision making and satisfy ourselves we have a legal basis on which to share the information.

## Your data protection rights

You have the right to ask us for copies of your personal data. It is important that the personal data we hold about you are accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal information changes. Thus the personal data may be modified or supplemented, and the consent to processing thereof may be revoked or restricted at any time by sending an email to [privacy@ecolint.ch](mailto:privacy@ecolint.ch). No charge will be made. In such a case, the provided personal data will be updated, blocked, or deleted immediately. Receiving electronic mails or messages from Ecolint may be revoked in the same manner at any time. We will not keep personal data longer than is necessary for the purpose or purposes for which they were collected

You further acknowledge that in order for Ecolint to provide certain services, notably education for your children, some personal information may be required, and that if you choose to revoke consent for the storage and processing of those data, this may entail the cancellation of your contract.

## Cookies

A cookie is a small text file stored by your browser that allows the website to “remember” your preferences (such as calendar settings and site bookmarks) on the site from visit to visit, or to maintain your “logged in” status when visiting protected areas. Browser cookies may also be used in remarketing campaigns to display paid content from Ecolint on partner websites. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site. Web browsers have settings allowing you to reject cookies, selectively accept cookies, or delete cookies previously accepted. Please be aware that rejecting or deleting cookies from our website may make certain functions and services unavailable to you.

## Log Files

Like most standard website servers, we use website statistic packages such as Google Analytics to analyze trends in how our website is accessed and utilized. Information monitored includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, geographic location of visitors (country, city), browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, time spent on pages, and keywords used to find our site via search engines. This information is anonymous and cannot be directly linked to individual users. We may use it to identify high-use or low-use areas of the site, pinpoint problem areas of the site, analyze broad demographic trends in our visitors, and make decisions about how to make it easier for people to find and navigate our website.

## Links

This and other Ecolint websites may contain links to external sites. This privacy notice does not cover how that organization processes personal information. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites, except those owned and maintained by Ecolint. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site(s) and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this and other Ecolint websites.

## Security

Ecolint websites take every precaution to protect our users' personal information. Whenever users submit personal information (such as contact info or credit card info) via online forms, registration, or online purchase, upon submission that information is encrypted via the highest level of security available (SSL). Servers that store personally identifiable information are in a secure environment. Under no circumstances are credit card numbers permanently stored on our website servers.

## Non-secured Communications

Posts to discussion forums, discussion boards, comments to blogs, and alumni events are viewable by other users. When these areas are not in a password protected area, they may be viewable by the general public. Please be aware of this when posting personal information in these areas.

## Contact Information

We keep our privacy notice under regular review to make sure it is up to date and accurate.

If users have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy and data protection practices, please contact us at [privacy@ecolint.ch](mailto:privacy@ecolint.ch).

_This policy is written in English and French. The English version should take precedence in case of discrepancy between these two texts._
